SAI PRASHANTH C - JOB POSITION

625 W 1st Street, #107 | 480-703-5615 | saiprash1993@yahoo.co.in | in.linkedin.com/in/saipc | webgyorwaves.com

SUMMARY

I'm a tech freak who spends more time on the computer than on doing any other activity, I have been using computers for 14 years (I'm 21 now), and so you can guess how that goes. I specialize in creating and designing websites and web apps, right from UI to getting down-n-dirty with server side scripting and everything in between, and am currently pursuing my Masters in Computer Science to learn more about creating AI, and improving Security.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, PHP, MySQL, C, C++, Java, XML, LESS, Node.js, Win8 App Dev, Android App Dev, Python, Clojure (in that order).

Frameworks/Libraries: jQuery, RaphaelJS, Bootstrap, Keylemon, jQueryUI, WinJS.

EXPERIENCE

Oct 2014 - Present	Faculty Advisor, Arizona State University
	· Serving as the faculty advisor to an undergrad student pursuing his thesis.
Aug 2014 - Present	Teaching Assistant, Arizona State University
	 In charge of the Capstone Project, for the final year students. Responsibilities include guiding, assessing, and grading the projects.
Aug 2014 - Present	Lead Front-end Engineer (Freelance), Dignity Health Corporation
	· Working on developing a new multi-factor authentication system . Details withheld due to NDA.
Jan 2013 - Present	Co-Founder, Webgyor Waves, Inc.
	· Co-founded the startup, Webgyor Waves in my 3 rd year of undergrad along with 5 other students,
	worked on developing websites and web apps – Shopping carts, Inventory Management Systems,
	Portfolio Websites.

RECENT PROJECTS

11202111 1 11002010	
Sep 2014 - Present	FallBreak – Fall detection system for Android Currently working on developing a Fall detection system using the Gyroscope and Accelerometer.
June 2014	Chain reaction - Browser Version Ported the popular game "Chain reaction" to the browser ensuring that it ran on as many devices as possible in the smallest possible size of 6kb, with no usage of any library/framework. Game runs offline too, more of an app than a browser game.
Jan 2014 - Apr 2014	Asynchronous Server Platform- Optimization over traditional platforms Created an asynchronous server using Node.js to support a real time game and a stock market system, made a comparison study with traditional systems built with PHP and Java, used benchmarks to showcase a Best case scenario of 328% improvement in the no. of requests serviced per second, and a worst case scenario of 109% compared to vanilla PHP/Java.
Mar 2014 - Apr 2014	Angel Ceramics Built a full blown inventory control system, complete with user authentication, adding, editing, removing items and exporting the data into other formats(MS Excel .xls, json, CSV etc) for a ceramics factory, built with PHP and MySQL on the backend, and using JS and AJAX to give the user a responsive control system.
Nov 2013 - Jan 2014	Photoathon

Website created for a Photography contest headed by leading cinematographers from the Indian Film Industry- www.photoathon.in. Conceptualized and designed the site. Uses JQueryUI and Supersized.js.

EDUCATION

2014- Present	MS in Computer Science, Arizona State University
2010-2014	B.E. in Computer Science and Engineering, MNM Jain Engineering College, Anna University. GPA 4.00
	Undergraduate Coursework: OOPS, Java Programming, Web Technologies, Operating Systems, DBMS,
	Data Structures and Algorithms, Theory of Computation.

HONORS AND AWARDS

Apr 2014	Best Outgoing Student 2010-2014, MNM Jain Engineering College, Anna University.
	Selected out of 113 Students.
Apr 2014	Most innovative undergrad project, MNM Jain Engineering College, Anna University.
	Selected out of 48 projects.
Nov 2013	Won 1 st place and a trip to Japan in "Talk your way to Japan" Contest, Hiyoshi Corporation.
	Selected out of 126 other participants from all over the state.
Aug 2011 – Mar 2014	Won 49 prizes in 34 State-level and National-level symposiums, in events like Web Designing(17),
	Debugging/Coding (7), Tech Quiz(9), Paper Presentations (9) etc